Now, the first thing that you need to do, even in a large group, no matter how difficult it is, are learn the students names.
It is very important that you learn their names, and that you are able to identify them by name.
Well you say, how can I learn two hundred students names, or more?
Well, there's some several things that you could do.
Obviously, the first one is name tags, which is my least favorite, but it's certainly an option.
You can also consider tents, name tents.
If you teach in a classroom or you're established in a classroom where there's some desks or large tables, put up name tents.
My favorite thing to do, is to have every student give me a photograph of themselves on a three by five index card with their name written on it.
And, that way I can look through the cards and I can learn to put names with faces.
Something else that you can do, is you can promise to your students that you will learn their names, and then that puts a lot of pressure on you because you don't want to break your promise.
Another option, which is not one of my all time favorites, but it works for certain settings and certain classrooms, is to have the students state their names before they ask a question, or before they speak, or when they are called on in class.
Something else that I have tried, that I've had a lot of success with is when I'm learning students names, if I get their name wrong, I have to take them out for a cup of coffee, and they really like that.
The, probably the most important thing about learning names is the willingness to look foolish.
The willingness to call Becky, Kathy thirteen times in a row, before you get it right.
But, I cannot stress how important it is, for you to learn your students names and give them an individuality in your classroom, where they're more than just a number.